And they made two little cuts. You can
see them. Just the smallest little cuts.
And he took my stomach out.
>> I'm joined here with Mr. John Geriago.
Very nice to meet you.
>> My pleasure to meet you.
>> I will get straight to the point. How
did you lose the weight? What is the
best and worst weight loss advice you
have ever heard?
>> The worst weight loss advice I ever
heard was to cut fat and cholesterol.
>> The worst?
>> The worst.
The worst.
Protein's good.
Carbohydrates are bad, especially
refined sugar.
But the sugar lobby in the United States
is so powerful that for decades they
convinced us that fat was the enemy.
>> Can I challenge you on this opinion?
>> Sure.
>> So, I agree with your point that big
companies want to make more money as
every company.
>> Sure.
>> So, they try to make their foods as
palatable as possible.
That's a strategy we like it or not.
Every company try to do that. Let's give
you an example. You said about protein
that that is good. Nowadays, protein is
a trend. So, every major company put
make a high protein product. Like let's
take chocolate high protein chocolates
high protein Do they want us healthy
because you said protein is good. I
agree with that. No, because people want
this so they can make more money
>> Yes.
>> out of this.
>> I don't I don't disagree. You're right.
>> I don't think their motive is to make us
They want to
make us consume more, but their target
is to make us
Yes, money. 100%.
Okay, so this is
>> on
the one side. On the other side, about
cholesterol, fats, etc. Long-term human
randomized clinical trials, yes, tend to
point us that saturated fats are bad,
not
>> Yes, of course.
>> Not every fat like let's take olive oil.
We have plenty.
>> Mono-mono-mono, yeah.
>> Monounsaturated, polyunsaturated.
>> Yes, they're good good fats.
>> So we agree that saturated fat is the is
the enemy.
>> Yes.
>> Total cholesterol, it depends. The we
have some people that they respond
highly to too much cholesterol because
they produce more themselves. So okay,
it depends on the but the harmful fats
are the saturated fats.
On the other side for carbs, there is a
common argument that people tend to make
that okay, carbs are bad because they
raise insulin. Insulin makes
carbohydrates stored as fat. Yes.
Okay, that's a mechanism but we are not
1 + 1 = 2. We have more that contribute
to our metabolism.
Believe it or not, we we know so much
about metabolism but it's so little at
the same time and the problem seems to
be that people overeat calories. The
average American, if I'm not mistaken,
consume 3,500
calories daily. That's the problem.
>> Yes, it is.
>> Not the one thing itself.
>> Yes. But if you're my age,
carbs are the the enemy.
>> Why?
>> Because
I'm not going to get
the exercise that I that my body
probably needs. My metabolism has slowed
over the years. I'm not going to burn
off those calories and and carbs are
going to be stored as fat.
>> Okay, you say cal- calories are
different from carbs.
>> Yeah.
>> Carbs is a macronutrient. And the I I
agree with you on the calories. You
should see the total calories. Also,
don't forget that we have carbs that are
rich in fiber
>> Yes, of course. Of course. Of course.
>> So
>> Yeah.
>> in my
not in my opinion I'm not going to say
to my opinion you should
watch your overall calories if it fits
your macros. Okay? And find something
that is sustainable for life. That's the
hard part that me people tend to miss.
Like if you say to me right now, George,
look, I cut out carbs and I lost the
weight this way. Go and say to you,
good. Good if it works for you. Okay,
good. Do it.
That's why I I'm asking your way.
>> Well, I'll tell you what happened.
I
when I
left the CIA
you get a lot of exercise as a CIA
officer. A lot.
When I left the CIA, I got a desk job
and I put on weight. And I decided I
really have to go on a diet. But I
didn't know really the best way to diet.
So I went to a nutritionist.
At the same time I was diagnosed with
diabetes, type 2 diabetes.
So the nutritionist put me on a diet. It
was 2,000 calories a day. It was up to
200 carbs, up to 20 g of saturated fat,
and as much protein as I wanted so long
as I kept within the calories and the
saturated fat.
So I cut out like lamb and most beef,
not not all the beef, but I ate much
more turkey and chicken.
And and uh tofu.
Although tofu gives you man boobs, now
they're telling us.
>> That's not true also.
>> Good. Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> I I only just read that.
>> And we have a recent meta-analysis that
proves that soy does not
>> Good. Because I eat a lot of soy and I
don't want to grow man boobs.
>> 100%.
>> So, um it took me a year, and I lost uh
70 lb, 32 kilos.
>> Congratulations. That's really
>> Thank you. Yeah,
it worked.
It was It was hard. But then with the
diabetes,
it it slowed my metabolism dramatically,
and little by little I put the weight
back on.
So, in
21,
my diabetes was bad enough that the
doctor put me on insulin.
I was on the maximum dosage of every
diabetes medication that is available.
Plus four shots of of uh insulin a day,
five on the on the weekends.
>> [snorts]
>> And um
and I ballooned.
Uh fatter than I've ever been in my
life.
So, I went back to the doctor,
and I said, "I don't know what's
happening to me. I'm not eating very
much at all." And he said, "I'll tell
you exactly what it is. When you started
on the insulin, it brought your
metabolism almost to a stop.
And that's why you can't burn the fat.
I'm going to send you an article to
read. I want you to read it, and then
come back and we'll talk about it." So,
he sends me this article from The
Lancet, the British uh the British uh
medical journal.
And it was written by a Scottish
surgeon.
And the Scottish surgeon wrote that he
was treating a woman
with stomach cancer.
And she also had uncontrolled diabetes.
My diabetes was uncontrolled. My A1C was
12.1.
It's supposed to be between four and
six.
So,
she had cancer in her stomach.
They took her stomach out,
and within 24 hours her pancreas started
to produce insulin again.
And so, he talked to other surgeons and
they said, "Yes, actually, I had the
same experience. I had a patient with
uncontrolled diabetes, we removed the
stomach and the pancreas started to work
again."
So,
I called this surgeon in Scotland. I
made an appointment to speak with him.
And he told me,
"It works. We don't know why it works.
We don't yet fully understand the human
body,
but it works. And there's almost no
downside, no side effects."
So, I said, "Well, is there anybody in
the United States that's doing this
surgery?" He said, "Yeah, there's a
surgeon in New York." So, I called the
surgeon in New York. And he said the
same thing. He said, "We don't
understand why it works, but it works."
I said, "Is this Are we talking about
like a bypass or a a sleeve or duodenal
switch?" He said, "No, those don't
work." He said, "The stomach has to
physically come out.
It's called a uh bariectomy." I said,
"Is there anybody in Washington that's
doing this surgery?" He said, "Yeah,
there's one surgeon in Arlington,
Virginia." I said, "I live in Arlington,
Virginia." He said, "His name is Dr.
Jihad Salama from Lebanon." So, I called
Dr. Salama. I go to see him and he says,
"The problem is this is an experimental
surgery, so insurance doesn't cover it."
I said, "How much does it cost?" He
said, "$17,000
with two nights in the hospital."
I said, "I don't have $17,000."
So, I borrowed it.
Went to the bank, I took out a loan for
$17,000. I gave him the $17,000.
And in September of 2022,
I went in.
I laid on the table, they put me to
sleep. He sat over here with the robot,
the toggles for the robot, and they made
two little cuts. You can see them. Just
the smallest little cuts.
And he took my stomach out.
I had to
I ate no solid food. I had only clear
liquids for 10 days. So, I was
completely empty, and um
my stomach had shrunk.
So, he they cut it, pulled it out, and
then they made a pouch out of my
intestine that holds a quarter of a cup,
just enough to fit in the palm of your
hand, and then he sewed me up.
So, I I had only liquids for another
week after that, and then I started
eating
pudding, puree,
soups, you know, things like that.
But, in the next 9 months, I lost 55
kilos, and I kept all of it off.
>> Congratulations.
>> And the most important thing is
I don't have diabetes anymore.
My A1C is normal.
Everything's normal.
>> Can I point something? I First of all,
congratulations.
It's very important
>> life-saving.
>> Congratulations. Really, I know it's
very hard. I know it's very very very
hard.
And you also go have to go through that.
Uh some food for thought, you lost the
weight you didn't gain the weight due to
diabetes. It's reverse.
>> It was Well, in the
In the beginning In the beginning, I I
I got fat, and that led to diabetes.
The second round was
the diabetes made me fat again.
>> That's what I'm going to say.
It's not usually true.
>> No, you're right. It's not usually true.
But, in my case, it was just because of
what it did to my metabolism.
>> Uh
>> do you think that
your overall calories changed like when
after you did the surgery? Most
probably, you started eating more
carefully. You reduce your calories due
to that.
>> Oh no, you're exactly right about that.
Um
I will tell you that
Yeah, I I I'm Greek. I love arni, right?
Who doesn't? And I just can't eat it
anymore. It's too it's too heavy, too
dense, too fatty. As soon as I eat it, I
throw up.
I I
I'm one of the 5% who get this surgery
that that did have side effects. So, I
had to have two follow-up surgeries.
Um
The The first one, I almost bled to
death internally.
I spent 8 days in the hospital in uh
January of last year. The first few days
after the surgery, I would throw up a
lot. And I thought, well, that's normal.
I just had this trauma to my body. They
took out my stomach. I'm throwing up.
That's just the way it's going to be.
I I happened to mention to the doctor, a
year and a half after the surgery. He
said, "Are you throwing up a lot?" And I
said, "Every day."
He said, "Really?" I said, "Yep, every
single day." He said, "That's not
normal.
You should have stopped throwing up a
week or 2 weeks after the surgery, not
18 months. You're still throwing up."
And um
they did my blood test I have to do
blood tests all the time.
Um and he determined that I was actually
malnourished.
So,
he said, "You have to eat more, but
there's a reason why you're throwing
up." He said, "I want to take a look do
the scope endoscopy."
So, I went in. He did an endoscopy. He
said, "You have a lot of scar tissue. I
need to I needed to cut it out." So, he
cut it out while he was down there.
And uh I said, "Okay." I felt fine. I I
didn't even have to spend the night in
the hospital. I was in there for 4 hours
and then they let me go.
And then I went to Greece with my son.
And I started throwing up again.
And so I got home.
There was one Saturday I was home like 2
days from Greece.
There was one Saturday
I worked from 10:00 in the morning to
10:00 at night.
And then I was tired. I went to bed at
10:00.
At
2:00 in the morning
I woke up and I was sweating. And that
happens sometimes now because my blood
sugar goes too low
rather than to be too high. So I
thought, "Mhm.
I must be having a low blood sugar
incident."
I don't remember
going downstairs.
But a half an hour later I woke up and I
was laying on the floor of the kitchen.
And I thought, "Shit, something's
happening to me. I hope I'm not having a
heart attack."
So I tried to get up and I fainted
again.
And another half hour passed.
>> [clears throat]
>> And I woke up again
laying on the floor.
I live with two guys who rent rooms in
my house. And I started shouting, "Help!
Help!"
Finally, one of them wakes up. It's 3:00
in the morning now. He comes down. He
said, "What happened to you?" I said, "I
don't know, but every time I try to get
up
I I pass out again."
So he wakes up the other guy. And
together they pick me up. I said, "Just
get me onto the couch."
So they put me on the couch and I'm
laying there. And I laid there for like
another hour.
And then I said
They gave me a Coca-Cola, full sugar.
And I didn't get any better from all
that sugar. And I said, "This must not
be
>> Hypoglycemic.
>> Hypoglycemia. I I don't know what's
happening to me.
And so I said, "Do me one more favor." I
said, "Just help me get back into bed.
I'll sleep this off, whatever it is."
What terrible
decision that is.
I said, "Just get me into bed." As soon
as they lifted me up, I passed out
again.
And then they called an ambulance.
So the ambulance comes
and they pick me up and they put me in a
chair and then they carry the chair to
the ambulance and they take me to the
hospital.
So I get to the hospital and all I
remember
is the doctor shouting my name. Can you
hear me, John? Can you hear me? And I
said, "Yes."
And he says, "We're taking you right
into surgery, okay?"
Surgery for what? I just said, "Okay."
And then when I woke up, it was 10:00 in
the morning.
The doctor was there standing at the
foot of the bed and I said, "What
happened to me?"
And he said, "You had a massive blood
clot
sitting on top of a massive ulcer right
at the surgical site."
And he said,
"When I came in,
my blood pressure was 80 over 52.
50 is death.
So I just made it." He said, "One more
hour it would have been too late."
So
I said, "What did you do?" He said,
"We We removed the blood clot.
We sewed up the ulcer." He said, "It was
giant, like that big."
And he said, "You were bleeding to death
internally."
He said something funny. He said,
"Didn't you realize that you were
bleeding? Like you didn't notice it when
you went to the bathroom?"
I said, "To tell you the truth,
I love ouzo
and so I eat black licorice all the time
and so it's always black."
He's like, "You got to stop doing that."
>> I stopped. I never ate licorice again.
So,
I felt it happening again in August.
I woke up in the middle of the night
and my girlfriend said, "Are you okay?"
And I said, "It's happening again. I can
feel it."
And she's like, "Oh my god, let's get to
the hospital." So, we drove to the
hospital. They admitted me straight into
surgery. When you get to be my age, you
know, I was always used to sitting in
the hospital for 6 hours waiting for
them to call your name. When you're my
age now, straight into the surgery. No
waiting, no nothing.
So, I went straight in and they said,
"Oh, you have a blood clot."
So, afterwards I saw the surgeon, Dr.
Solomon. He said, "You're one of those
5%
that this has led to blood clots."
>> Oh my god.
>> So, I said, "Well, you know what? I
would rather deal with blood clots and
be skinny
than to be fat and diabetic."
So, now I take a blood thinner
and everything's good. Knock on wood.
>> Thanks God, first of all, and uh
I it's very unfortunate you have to go
through that.
>> Yeah.
>> Really. Moving forward to other
questions.
>> I like to describe myself
politically as a member of the
libertarian left.
Some libertarians will tell you there is
no such thing as the libertarian left,
that the libertarian movement by its
nature is a right-wing movement. I
disagree strongly.
Although I walk a fine line. So,
in the in the United States,
libertarianism
is
an ideology of self-sufficiency.
I don't need anything from the
government. I take care of myself,
right? But at the same time, that means
I hate the police.
I hate the military. I hate the
intelligence services. Any libertarian
would say this.
Um, and that's seen as very
conservative. Self-sufficiency.
I don't hate
the military or the
intelligence services. I do hate the
police cuz they're all [__]
>> Okay.
>> But, um
But, I also believe in what's called a
social safety net.
I believe that we should take care of
old people. I believe that we should
take care of poor people. I believe that
we should welcome refugees and
immigrants.
Um
Most libertarians don't agree with that.
But, I also believe that what Ronald
Reagan said in 1984 was correct. He
said, "The problem is I I'm sorry. He
said, "Government is the problem, not
the solution to the problem."
And I believe that that's right.
It is the problem. Government is
corrupt. By its nature, it's corrupt.
You know, in the United States, we like
to think that we are so much better than
everybody else. We're smarter than
everybody else. We're more honest than
everybody else. We're more
forward-thinking than everybody else.
And that's just not true.
Corruption is a terrible problem in the
United States. Terrible. We're not
better than everybody else. Besides the
fact that we are constantly invading
countries, bombing countries,
overthrowing governments. What's that
all about?
There are only three ways that you can
go into another country. Three legal
ways to go into another country. With
the approval of the United Nations
Security Council.
At the invitation of that other country.
Or if that other country attacks you
first.
We never meet any of those three
criteria.
Ah, we want to overthrow Venezuela? No
problem. We just go in. we kidnap the
president, we overthrow the government.
We don't like Iran's politics, no
problem. We're just going to bomb them.
We don't like Saddam Hussein, we're
going to overthrow him and invade and
occupy his country.
Al-Qaeda is in Afghanistan, we're going
to push them out, but we're also going
to overthrow the Afghan government and
we're going to occupy that for 20 years.
That's
None of that is legal.
>> So, you changed your opinion because you
are appearing to say that you always
thought
>> We were the good guys.
>> You are the good guys.
>> Yeah.
>> Is that
It's brainwashed, basically inside
world, and everyone thinks that they
>> Americans are
>> Most Americans are.
>> Yeah.
>> What was your last meal before
sentencing, and what was your first meal
after?
>> They were the same meal.
>> Really?
>> [laughter]
>> My my now ex-wife
makes the most delicious
Japanese yellow curry
from scratch
with
cubes of pork, potato, carrot, celery,
peas over rice.
>> Sounds delicious.
>> loved it.
>> Delicious.
>> [laughter]
>> I want to try that. I have never tried
the
>> It's fantastic.
>> What is something crazy you did with
your diet during operations? Like, let's
say
where are
days when you didn't eat anything at
all?
>> Yeah. Yeah, there were days.
>> Days?
>> There were days when I didn't eat
anything at all. At one time, we were
doing an operation, I knew it was going
to be 14 hours before I could
I could This is going to sound stupid,
and because you're a nutrition
professional, you're going to yell at
me.
I knew I wasn't going to have any food
at all for 14 hours.
And the only thing that was available to
me was a big container of mango juice.
So, I bought the mango juice.
>> Better than that, nothing than that.
>> Better than nothing. Pure sugar.
But, that's I would just sip it over the
course of 14 hours and it kept me from
being hungry the whole time.
>> Yeah, again, better than nothing.
Really, it's uh
Okay, very interesting.
What would a CIA agent never order at a
restaurant like during operations?
>> Seafood, but especially shellfish.
Because it's so common to get sick from
shellfish. And if you get E. coli or
Giardia or Shigella from shellfish and
you're flat on your back and you're
[__] yourself and you have a fever
and you can't participate in the
operation, you're no good to anybody.
>> What is your favorite Cypriot food?
>> You know, it's going to sound silly.
I've been eating for the last 10 days
only Cypriot food. And you I don't want
to eat or whatever because you can get
them everywhere.
I have to say the cheeses in Cyprus are
so much more sophisticated than the
cheeses in Greece.
>> Really?
>> So much more sophisticated, so much more
subtle.
You know? Like in Greece, of course,
everybody has feta at every meal and we
have kasseri, we have kefalotyri,
kefalograviera,
all these different
cheeses.
But most of them are variations on each
other.
>> Mhm.
>> Here,
and I have no idea why this is the case.
Here, each cheese
stands independently by itself. This one
is very nutty. This one tastes like
pine. This one you can put with meli.
This one, halloumi, is, you know, the
the flagship of all the cheeses.
Every cheese is
completely independent of every other
cheese. And so I've eaten 20 different
kinds of Cypriot cheese this week. I I
will add one thing about halloumi. My
kids love halloumi. We all do. But only
until 5 years ago, you couldn't buy it
in the United States except at a
specialty cheese shop or Whole Foods.
And Whole Foods is very expensive.
We Sometimes the Greek store would have
it. Usually not cuz dirty little secret,
most of the Greek stores are not owned
by Greeks. They're owned by Egyptians.
>> Yes.
>> So they sneak in these Egyptian
products. Yeah.
>> So
only 5 years ago I started finding
halloumi at the grocery store. Now it's
everywhere. So now I buy it all the
time.
The halloumi here in Cyprus is saltier
than American halloumi. I prefer the
Cypriot one.
>> Super.
>> Um but but these other cheeses, it's
been a revelation to me.
It's the best.
>> You talk about halloumi but I thought
you were were going to talk about
sheftalia, let's say or
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah. Well, sheftalia, I had sheftalia
on Tuesday.
>> Okay.
>> And it was great.
But the cheeses, it's like, oh my god,
it's these cheeses and
>> stand out.
>> Yeah.
>> So tzatziki or tirokafteri?
>> Definitely tzatziki.
>> Gyros or souvlaki?
>> Gyros.
>> Feta or halloumi?
>> I'm going to have to say halloumi.
>> Thank you for that. Freddo espresso or
freddo cappuccino?
>> Cappuccino.
>> Freddo
cappuccino or freddo
>> Freddo freddo cappuccino. I'll tell you
why.
Because I love coffee so much, I drink
so much coffee every day, all day
that
you just get more if the if they add the
gala for the cappuccino.
>> Okay.
>> So, I just feel like I'm getting more
coffee that way.
>> I think it's the worst coffee that ever
existed and people know me for that and
let me tell you why. You get a freddo
cappuccino, you put the straw, right?
I usually wake up, want to drink my
coffee immediately to get that caffeine
going.
When you drink a freddo cappuccino with
a straw, you
you drink a freddo espresso, not the
other sits on the top.
>> I don't want to drink it.
>> Okay, that's the only
right way. Okay.
>> Plus another thing, they do this in
Cyprus and they do it in Greece, too.
The straw is too small.
>> [laughter]
>> You can't get anything out of that. So,
you know, you can try to mix it around,
but you're right, you're going to get
the the espresso and then it's just foam
and milk on the top. So, I don't use the
straw.
>> Okay, I have a beef with freddo
cappuccino. I usually say, "Why? Why?" I
don't want to wait 10 minutes to melt
from the
milk to melt the
>> I'll tell you another thing. When I was
in Rhodes with my son last
last year.
We met my cousin Christo
uh for coffee in the morning and he says
to me, I was having a frappe, which I
always get. Frappe metrio.
>> Yes.
>> Not for breakfast, but later in the day.
And he says, "Why Why do you drink this
shit?" he says. I said, "Why? Frappedes
are good."
And he said, "It's Nescafe. It's [__]
coffee." He said, "Get a freddo espresso
or freddo cappuccino."
I was like, "All right. All right." So,
I did.
And I thought, "Now, he's right. This is
better. It's higher quality coffee. They
grind the beans. It's not coming from a
can of of Nescafe."
He was right.
>> And fun fact,
instant coffee and the fresh ground
coffee have not exactly the same, but
similar health effects.
They don't differ
>> Really?
>> Really.
>> So, it doesn't lose any of the
>> The antioxidant also the heart
protecting
nutrients.
>> Right.
>> Uh I also finding finding this out I was
like I don't know way, but we have
plenty of research so
>> And I will say I do pay attention to
coffee research. I do. Whenever there's
a new study, I make sure to go through
the whole study.
>> Great research. The health benefits of
cold And another fun fact, most US
people get mostly their antioxidants
from coffee.
>> Because we don't eat berries and acai
and
>> Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
>> So dumb.
>> But it's something at least at least.
So, something more interesting. What is
one life lesson you wish you knew at my
age that you had to learn the hard way?
>> That you can't trust anybody.
anybody.
I allowed myself to trust one person.
And that was the person that betrayed
me.
They tell you at the CIA, "Don't trust
anybody. Don't even trust me."
Yeah, I should have listened.
>> My dad always says this to me and
I don't really listen to him. I tend to
trust people.
>> Yeah, I do too.
>> I I think I I'm selfish person. I think,
"Oh, I know him. He won't."
I know him. I I get the vibes and I
stand on the vibes. I see the vibes, but
>> Uh-huh.
>> Hearing that from you it's
>> Yeah, it's a shame. I hate to say it.
It's a shame, but that's a hard lesson
that I learned.
>> Thanks for that. So, can you tell us a
story you've never shared before due to
its unsettling details?
>> You know, I actually can't. And I'll
tell you what I'll tell you why.
The stories that I tell The The reason
that I repeat many of the stories that I
tell is because those are the stories
that have been declassified.
>> Mhm.
>> So, I'll write a book. I've written nine
books. I write a book and then I have to
send it to the CIA for clearance. And
then they'll black out things that are
classified. And then I have to say, "No,
I want to challenge what you blacked out
here. It shouldn't be classified for
these reasons." Sometimes I win,
sometimes I lose.
But, everything that they've finally
approved I've already told.
>> Okay.
That's a great answer.
>> But, I I I'll tell you a joke.
>> Okay.
>> It's a joke that the director of the
Ethniki Ypiresia Pliroforion,
the Greek Intelligence Service, told me.
>> Okay.
>> He said that there was
>> Great accent, Greek also.
>> Hey, thank you.
>> Sorry for interrupting.
>> He There was a There was a Russian
intelligence officer,
an American intelligence officer, and a
Greek intelligence officer. And they all
went out together.
And they're drinking. And the Russian
says,
"We have a bomb that is so big it can
blow up an entire city."
And the American says, "We have a bomb
that's so big
we can blow up an entire region."
And the Greek says,
"My boot so is so big
>> [laughter]
>> that 10 birds can land on it
side by side."
And they keep drinking, drinking,
drinking, and they get really drunk.
And the Russian says, "You know what?
We don't really have a bomb that's so
big to blow up a whole city."
And the American says, "We don't have We
don't have a bomb that's so big to blow
up an entire region."
And then the Greek says,
"When the 10th bird lands, he usually
asks to go
>> [laughter]
>> like this."
>> That's [laughter] a good one.
>> I thought that was a good one.
>> That's a great one.
>> And the last thing that I I saw the
clips, not all of them of course, but
many clips and people
tend to say down the comments that based
on how you tell your stories, you don't
have PTSD, but rather a sense of
nostalgia. Is that true? [laughter]
>> What a terrible thing to say.
>> [laughter]
>> Um
>> [clears throat]
>> Sure.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> Yeah, I do.
>> Explain.
>> I do. I I have to say I thoroughly
enjoyed my career.
9/11 turned everybody into stone-cold
murderers. I hate to say that. A friend
of mine posted on Facebook the other day
that his brother-in-law just got out of
prison. He said, "My brother-in-law was
20 years in prison for a murder. I'm I
met a murderer," he said. I said, "Try
working at the CIA for 15 years when
you're the only person who's not a
murderer."
You know?
>> Yes.
>> After 9/11
I was I was leaving for for the airport
to go to Pakistan. I went into the
office to say goodbye because, you know,
we didn't know. Am I going to come home?
I hope I can come home. I don't know.
I mean, two of my colleagues didn't come
home.
Or they couldn't came home in a box.
So, I went to say goodbye to everybody
and my boss gives me this big hug
and he says, "Be careful. Be careful." I
said, "I'm going to be careful." He He
served in Greece for years, so he says
to me, "The matia sou theka," he says.
American guy, but his Greek was
absolutely perfect. He says, "The matia
sou theka." I said, "Thank you, John."
And then as he's hugging me, he whispers
to me, "Kill them all."
And I said, "Really?"
"We've already gotten there?
And he says kill them all.
I thought about that the whole way to
the to the airport. Like oh man.
>> Thanks John.
>> Mhm.
Yeah.
>> Thank you John.
>> Thank you. Good to talk to you.
>> Pleasure to meet you.
>> The pleasure is all mine. Thank you.